# Changyeon Kim

🛮 (+82) 10-9020-3925 | 🗷 changyeon.kim@kaist.ac.kr | 🍪 changyeon.page | 🖸 csmile-1006 | 😂 Changyeon Kim

# Research Interest

My research interest lies in the intersection of AI and robot learning. Specifically, I am committed to designing algorithms tailored for complex environments lacking well-defined rewards by learning suitable reward functions utilizing human preferences or foundational vision language models. In addition, I am interested in related areas of decision-making problems, including (M)LLM agents, offline RL, and generalization in RL.

# **Education**

#### **Korea Advanced Institute of Science and Technology**

PHD IN ARTIFICIAL INTELLIGENCE

Advisor: Jinwoo Shin and Kimin Lee

**Korea Advanced Institute of Science and Technology** 

B.Sc. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE AND MATHEMATICS (MINOR)

Daejeon, S.Korea

Mar. 2022 - Present

Daejeon, S.Korea

Mar. 2016 - Feb. 2021

# **Publications**

C: Conference, W: Workshop, P: Preprint, \*: Equal contribution

#### [P1] Subtask-Aware Visual Reward Learning from Segmented Demonstrations

CHANGYEON KIM, MINHO HEO, DOOHYUN LEE, JINWOO SHIN, HONGLAK LEE, KIMIN LEE, JOSEPH J LIM

• Preprint (Available upon request).

#### [W2] B-MoCA: Benchmarking Mobile Device Control Agents across Diverse Configurations

Vienna, Austria

May, 2024.

Juyong Lee, Taywon Min, Minyong Ahn, Dongyoon Hahm, Haeone Lee, **Changyeon Kim**, Kimin Lee

 ICLR 2024 Workshop on Generative Models for Decision Making (ICLRW), Spotlight

#### [C3] Guide Your Agent with Adaptive Multimodal Rewards

New Orleans, USA

**CHANGYEON KIM**, YOUNGGYO SEO, HAO LIU, LISA LEE, JINWOO SHIN, HONGLAK LEE, KIMIN LEE

Dec, 2023.

- Conference on Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS), 2023.
- · A preliminary version appeared at ICML 2023 Workshop on New Frontiers in Learning, Control, and Dynamical Systems (ICMLW)

#### [C2] Preference Transformer: Modeling Human Preferences using Transformers for RL

Kigali, Rwanda

CHANGYEON KIM\*, JONGJIN PARK\*, JINWOO SHIN, HONGLAK LEE, PIETER ABBEEL, KIMIN LEE

May, 2023.

• International Conference on Learning Representations (ICLR), 2023.

# [W1] Dynamics-Augmented Decision Transformer for Offline Dynamics Generalization

New Orleans, LA, USA

**Changyeon Kim**\*, Junsu Kim\*, Younggyo Seo, Kimin Lee, Honglak Lee, Jinwoo Shin

Nov, 2022.

• NeurIPS 2022 Workshop on Offline Reinforcement Learning (NeurIPSW)

#### [C1] Collecting the Public Perception of AI and Robot Rights

Online

Gabriel Lima, **Changyeon Kim**, Seungho Ryu, Chihyoung Jeon, Meeyoung Cha

Oct, 2020.

• Conference on Computer-Supported Cooperative Work and Social Computing (CSCW), 2020.

# [P1] MOI-Mixer: Improving MLP-Mixer with Multi Order Interactions in Sequential Recommendation

Hojoon Lee, Dongyoon Hwang, Sunghwan Hong, **Changyeon Kim**, Seungryong Kim, Jaegul Choo

• ArXiv Preprint.

# Work Experience

**External Collaborator** 

Seoul, KAIST

JOSEPH J. LIM (KAIST)

Mar. 2024 - June. 2024

• Developed a visual reward learning algorithm [P1] for solving complex long-horizon robotic manipulations.

Remote

External Collaborator

Apr. 2023 - Aug. 2023

• Developed an imitation learning algorithm [C3] using multimodal representations for improving generalization ability in unseen variations.

June 28, 2024 Changyeon Kim · Résumé

External Collaborator Remote

HONGLAK LEE (UNIVERSITY OF MICHIGAN)

Mar. 2022 - June. 2024

- Developed an imitation learning algorithm [C3] using multimodal representations for improving generalization ability in unseen variations.
- Developed a reinforcement learning algorithm [W1] for improving generalization ability in varying dynamics.
- Developed a preference-based reinforcement learning algorithm [C2] for modeling non-Markovian human preferences.
- · Developed a visual reward learning algorithm [P1] for solving complex long-horizon robotic manipulations.

#### **Machine Learning Engineer**

Seongnam, S.Korea
Dec. 2020 - Feb. 2022

Kakao, Recommendation Team

- Developed ML platform for recommendation system.
- Developed Python backend for a web application providing data analysis and visualization of Kakao data.
- · Implemented data pipeline from user feedback to refined user-item interaction matrix data.
- Deployed DropoutNet for providing qualitative recommendations to cold-start users.

Research Intern Seongnam, S.Korea

Kakao, Recommendation Team

Developed an advanced similar recommendation model for Piccoma (cartoon platform of Kakao Japan).

Conducted research on relationships between offline/online evaluation on the recommendation system.

Research Intern Daejeon, S.Korea

DATA SCIENCE GROUP, INSTITUTE OF BASIC SCIENCE

Jul. 2019 - Nov. 2020

Jun. 2020 - Aug. 2020

- · Conducted research on how much human rights can be granted to robots using AMT (Amazon Mechanical Turk) [C1].
- Implemented BiLSTM model for extracting game higlight by game log.
- Conducted research identifying the "Pilgrimage" articles and analyzing its pattern in Naver News corpora.

Research Interen Seoul, S.Korea

NETMARBLE Jun. 2018 - Aug. 2018

- Implemented algorithm for detecting "fraud" account in online-game
- · Analyzed repetitive group reaction from time-series data of game activities.

# Honors & Awards

2023	<b>Travel Award</b> , Conference on Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS)	New Orleans, USA
2023	<b>Scholarship</b> , KAIST-Google Partnership Program	Daejeon, S.Korea
2023	East Asia Student Travel Grant, Google	New Orleans, USA
2023	Travel Award, International Conference on Learning Representations (ICLR)	Kigali, Rwanda
2019	Dean's List (Fall Semester), Department of Engineering, KAIST	Daejeon, S.Korea
2019	Line Scholarship (Fall Semester), School of Computing, KAIST	Daejeon, S.Korea
2017 - 19	National Science and Engineering Scholarship, Korea Ministry of Science and ICT	Daejeon, S.Korea
2017	Kwanjeong Scholarship (Spring Semester), KAIST	Daejeon, S.Korea

## Invited Talks\_

## **Guide Your Agent with Adaptive Multimodal Rewards**

NeurIPS 2023

IMITATION LEARNING FRAMEWORK WITH VLM REWARDS FOR BETTER GENERALIZATION

• LG AI Research, New Orleans, USA (2023)

## Academic Services

Conference Reviewer ICML (2024), NeurIPS (2024)

Workshop Reviewer ICML Workshop on New Frontiers in Learning, Control, and Dynamical Systems (Frontiers4LCD) 2023

#### Skills\_

**ML/DL** Pytorch, Pytorch-lightning, JAX/Flax

**Programming** Python, C++

Big Data Kafka, SQL, MongoDB, Hadoop, Trino(Presto)

**DevOps** Git, Docker, Kubernetes

Languages Korean (Native), English (Fluent), Japanese (Advanced)